tropo.com 2017-07-01

# Privacy Policy Tropo | Tropo - Cloud API for Voice and Messaging

**Effective Date:   August 31st, 2015**

The terms “you,” “your,” and “yours” refer to the customer using our websites, www.voxeolabs.com, www.phono.com and [www.tropo.com](http://www.tropo.com/), all owned and operated by Tropo LLC, and specifically exclude users of third-party applications developed using Tropo LLC services. The terms “Company,” “we,” “us,” and “our” refer to Tropo LLC (Tropo). This Privacy Policy is governed by our Terms of Service. By using this website, you consent to the data practices described in this statement.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to users of third-party applications developed using Tropo services.  The collection, use, storage and disclosure of information collected from users of each third-party application is governed by the policies of the third party that created it.  Tropo is not responsible for the practices of third parties, including third-party developers. With respect to user information and otherwise, Tropo will not be liable to you for any harm that arises out of or in any way relates to the acts or failures to act of any third party.

**Personal Information Collection and Use**

Tropo does collect personal information directly from subscribers during the product registration process. “Personal information” is any information that can be used to identify an individual, and may include name, address, email address, phone number, or payment card number.

The personal information we collect includes but is not limited to your name, email address, phone number to initially register and then subsequently address and credit card if you choose to buy the service. We use this information to provide services and customer support to you.

Tropo uses the subscriber personal information for its own internal marketing / product update email campaigns but offers the subscribers the opportunity, during the registration process to choose whether their personal information is to be used for this purpose. You can opt out by following the unsubscribe option included in each email.

**Personal Information Sharing**

Tropo respects your privacy. We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy.  Any business-related or personal information you provide to us — including your name and similar identifying information, such as your address, telephone number, and e-mail address — will not be released, sold, or rented to any entities or individuals outside of Tropo, except as necessary to provide services or products you specifically request.

We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as payment processing. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us, and will be required to adhere to the privacy protections provided in this Privacy Policy.

We may also disclose your personal information:

  * as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process
  * when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or in response to an official government request,
  * if Tropo is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information,
  * to any other third party with your prior consent to do so.

**The Security of Your Personal Information**

We will take reasonable precautions to protect personal information in our possession from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. We follow generally accepted industry standards, like secure socket layers (SSL) to protect the personal information submitted to us such as credit card number, both during transmission and once we receive it, as well as logical and physical access controls for user access to personal information. No method of transmission over the Internet or method of electronic storage is, however, 100% secure. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

**Access to Personal Information**

Tropo will provide reasonable assistance to its subscribers to provide access to personal information that it holds on their behalf. Tropo permits its subscribers (once logged into their account) the ability to correct, amend, or delete any personal information which is inaccurate or incomplete via their profile page. We will respond to any requests to support@tropo.com for personal information or changes thereof within 30 days.

If you choose to close your Tropo account or your account is not used for a prolonged period, we will retain your account information as a historical business audit record only. We archive all closed accounts, and delete the users’ ability to log into them or to recover and/or change password. We also no longer send automated correspondence about your closed account via email. From date of closure of your account, we will only use your account information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, protect against fraud, and enforce our agreements.

**Data Integrity**

Tropo, Inc. does not process personal information in a way that is incompatible with the purposes for which it was collected or with the instructions provided by the subscriber.  Tropo, Inc. takes reasonable steps to ensure that personal information is reliable for its intended use, accurate, complete, and current.

**Cookies / Tracking Technologies**

We use cookies on this site. A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes. We link the information we store in cookies to personal information you submit while on our site. We link these cookies for the purpose of auto log-in as well as creation and management of your accounts and applications.

We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser.  A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s “help” directory.

If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some areas of our site, such as contests or surveys, will be limited.

The use of cookies by our partners and affiliates is not covered by our privacy statement. We do not have access to or control over these cookies.

As is true of most web sites, we use cookies to gather certain information automatically and store it in log files.  This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data.

Tropo, Inc. may directly or allow companies that we work with to use technologies such as beacons, tags and scripts in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports from our partners based on the use of these technologies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

**Forums and Comments**

If you use the forum or post comments on this website, you should be aware that any personal information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. Tropo is not responsible for any personal information you choose to submit. You can request the removal of your personal information from our community forum, by contacting us at labs@tropo.com. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

**Links to Other Sites**

This website may contain links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by us. Please be aware that Tropo is not responsible for the privacy policies of such other sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personal information. This privacy policy applies only to information collected by this website.

**Single Sign On**

You can log in to our support site using Twitter. This service will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form. Services like these can give you the option to post information about your activities on this website to your profile page to share with others within your network.  Please see [Twitter’s privacy policy](https://twitter.com/privacy?lang=en) for more about what personal information Twitter may collect about you when you use Twitter’s single sign-on service, and how that information may be used.

**Social Media Widgets**

Our web site includes social media features, such as the Facebook Like button and widgets, the ShareThis button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our website. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

**Children’s Privacy**

Tropo’s website and its online services are not designed for use by children under the age of 13, and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13 online. If we learn that we have collected personal information on a child under the age of 13 online, we will delete that data from our systems.

**Privacy Rights for California Residents**

Residents of the State of California, under California Civil Code § 1798.83, have the right to request from companies conducting business in California a list of all third parties to which the company has disclosed personal information during the preceding year for direct marketing purposes. Alternatively, the law provides that if the company has a privacy policy that gives either an opt-out or opt-in choice for use of your personal information by third parties (such as advertisers) for marketing purposes, the company may instead provide you with information on how to exercise your disclosure choice options.

Tropo qualifies for the alternative option. We have a comprehensive privacy statement, and provide you with details on how you may either opt-out or opt-in to the use of your personal information by third parties for direct marketing purposes. Therefore, we are not required to maintain or disclose a list of the third parties that received your personal information for marketing purposes during the preceding year.

If you are a California resident and request information about how to exercise your third party disclosure choices, please [email us](mailto:support@tropo.com) your request.

**Your Consent To This Privacy Policy**

By using Tropo you agree to this Privacy Policy. This is our entire and exclusive Privacy Policy and it supersedes any earlier version. Our Terms of Service take precedence over any conflicting Privacy Policy provision. We may change this Privacy Policy by posting a new version of this Privacy Policy on this website which it is your responsibility to review. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email or by means of a notice on this site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this Privacy Policy to stay informed about how we are protecting the personal information we collect. Your continued use of this website constitutes your agreement to this Privacy Statement and any updates.

Any questions or concerns regarding the use or disclosure of personal information should be directed to Tropo through the contact information listed below:

Email:  [support@tropo.com](mailto:support@tropo.com)

Tropo LLC  
170 West Tasman Drive  
San Jose, CA 95134  
Phone: +1 408-526-4000
